Finding Aid for Elvira Vogel papers, 1952-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Elvira Vogel papers
1952-1990
Vogel, Elvira.
9474 Aa 2
Educator from Washtenaw County, Michigan. Subject files concern the Western Washtenaw Area PTA, the Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers, the Washtenaw County School Officers Association, and the Washtenaw Intermediate School District.
5.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mrs. Vogel donated her papers to the Bentley Historical Library in 1993 (Donor no. 7908 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Elvira Vogel was an educator with the Washtenaw Intermediate School District.
The Elvira Vogel papers document her participation in various Washtenaw County educational organizations. The Vogel collection has been arranged into series of records for each of these organizations.
Subjects:
Education--Michigan.; Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers.; Parents' and teachers' associations--Michigan.; Vogel, Elvira.; Washtenaw County School Officers Association.; Washtenaw Intermediate School District.; Western Washtenaw Area PTA (Mich.)
- Western Washtenaw Area PTA, 1952-1963
  The Western Washtenaw Area PTA series consists of papers for the years 1952-1963, and includes bylaws and minutes of meetings.
  - Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Historian's Book, 1954-1963 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1952-1963 (Box 1)
  - Officers (mid-1950s) (Box 1)
  - Social Issues (Boys' Vocational School) (Box 1)
- Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1956-1963
  The Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers series (1956-1963) includes the papers that Mrs. Vogel collected when she attended a couple of statewide PTA leadership workshops.
  - Correspondence from committee chairs to locals, 1956-1957; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Leadership training workshop, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Resolutions from convention, 1963 (Box 1)
- Washtenaw County School Officers Association, 1968-1976
  The Washtenaw County School Officers Association series (1968-1976) is one folder of materials that was collected by her husband, Louis Vogel, when he was in the leadership of the organization.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Washtenaw Intermediate School District, 1960-1990
  The Washtenaw Intermediate School District (WISD) series (1960-1990) at 5 linear feet is the largest series in the collection and documents Vogel's more than thirty years of service with the school district. Most of her work focused on providing education and vocational training to the physically disabled and children with learning and emotional/behavioral disabilities. The papers strongly reflect this focus. The WISD series consists of a subseries of alphabetical topical files (2 linear feet) and a subseries of printed materials (3 linear feet) relating to the WISD's budgets and special education services. The printed materials span many years, beginning in 1964 and extending up to 1990.
  - Accountability (clippings) (Box 1)
  - Alternative education (Box 1)
  - Barrier free (program review) (Box 1)
  - Bilingual education (clippings) (Box 1)
  - "Black English" (clippings and pamphlet) (Box 1)
  - Blind, program for (Box 1)
  - Board meetings, 1958-1962 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Building, funding for (Box 1)
  - Business, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Career education planning district, #43 (Box 1)
  - Career education, general (Box 1)
  - Career technical center, Ypsilanti (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1967-1974 (Box 1)
  - Computing services for county, 1972 (Box 1)
  - (COPE) Center for Occupational and Personalized Education, Inc. annual report, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Data processing center (Box 1)
  - Deaf and hearing impaired (Box 1)
  - Department of Education, formation of (Box 1)
  - Desegregation (clippings) (Box 1)
  - Elected board members and school officials (Box 1)
  - Energy (Box 1)
  - Evaluation of teachers (clippings) (Box 1)
  - Family planning (clippings and correspondence) (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
  - Grading (clippings) (Box 1)
  - Head Start (Box 1)
  - Headlee amendment (clippings) (Box 1)
  - High Point-behavior management system, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - High Scope (clippings) (Box 1)
  - Horseback riding for handicapped (clippings and pamphlet) (Box 1)
  - Inservice workshops for staff development, 1977-1982 (Box 2)
  - Insurance-building and health (Box 2)
  - Juvenile court annual report, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Juvenile detention home (Box 2)
  - Loch Alpine Subdivision, school district property transfer hearing (Box 2)
  - Mainstreaming handicapped into schools (Box 2)
  - Millage for special education, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Newsletter (Box 2)
  - Organization flow chart (Box 2)
  - Parent advisory council (Box 2)
  - Pebble Creek day program for severely emotionally disturbed (Box 2)
  - Personal (Box 2)
  - Personnel policy, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Physically and Otherwise Health Impaired (POHI) Special program for physically and otherwise health impaired youngsters (Box 2)
  - Professional development (Box 2)
  - Project find (Box 2)
  - Publicity (Box 2)
  - Schwartz property, purchase of (Box 2)
  - Schools (Box 2)
  - Special education, 1959-1969; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - St. Louis School for Boys, Chelsea (Box 2)
  - Superintendent's goals, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Talented and gifted students (Box 2)
  - Transfer of property of Ann Arbor School District to Saline School District, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Vocational education
    - Building plans, proposal (Box 3)
    - Chelsea, Dexter, Manchester, Milan, Saline (Box 3)
    - For special education students (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Planning (Box 3)
    - Rehabilitation (Box 3)
  - Wages, teachers and administrators (Box 3)
  - Washtenaw school officers organization (Box 3)
  - Young adult program (Box 3)
  - Young mothers program (Box 3)
  - Youth facilities network, 1973-1976 (Box 3)
  - Youth services bureau
    - General (Box 3)
    - Grant application for, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
    - Guide, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Printed materials
    - Annual reports, 1968-1989 (Box 4)
    - Audits, 1964-1977 (Box 4)
    - Budgets, 1969-1978; 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Educational directories, 1970-1976 (Box 5)
    - Special education directories, 1977-1987 (Box 5)
    - Special education office/staff manuals of policies, 1967-1978 (Box 5)
    - Special education, plans for delivery of, for school years, 1970-1985 (Box 6)